shobhit singh

front-end developer

shobhit singh

18012 graan voor visch hoofddorp, 2132 GA

https://shobhit-portfolio.herokuapp.com

+31 644777939

shobhit5@hotmail.com

web developer and professional googler with a total of 4.5 years of experience using JavaScript. using React JS nowadays to migrate old apps and explore. familiar with identity and access management practices and industry standards.

skills

Main Skills: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, React JS, Node JS, XML, JSON, NPM, expert at googling stuff.

Also Familiar with: TypeScript, JAVA, PYTHON, Selenium,

Plenty of experience in: IBM security access manager, LDAP, IBM Directory server, OIDC, OAuth 2.0, SAML2.0, JWT, TAM

Working in Agile methodology, Design Thinking, Tableau

experience

infosys limited / technical analyst

AUG 2018 - PRESENT, Amsterdam, Netherlands

Eased doing inspection and correction on test cases being run on multiple STB and VOD devices with the help of a single application.

Easier report generation for all dev related activities and email distribution using Web app.

Reduced debugging time by half with the help of dashboard to monitor and update the server details.

Improved efficiency by automating health checks for the various web applications authentication.

Migration of API based application to SPA for faster validations.

Multiple platform (Web, App) support with APIs using NodeJS and Passport JS (provide strong Access Control).

Simplified knowledge sharing and instruction with the help of documentation.

Participation in knowledge transfer sessions which helps teams with insights of technical aspects of the module.

Actively monitoring the proper deployment of applications from development to production.

infosys limited / software engineer

Aug 2015 - Aug 2018, Bangalore India

Automated pick up of a file, extract and store information regarding ads for future processing.

Employee management web app using angularJS and Okta access prov

Implemented solutions for maintaining and verifying the identities of the users and providing appropriate access to them.

Setting up the reverse proxy, creating the Junctions and attaching the ACL's, Pops for controlling the application access.

Provide additional checks using second/Multi-factor authentication for identity verification with QR code, OTP (SMS, Email), FIDO 2.0.

Creation of JAVA application to extend features of ISAM.

Maintaining user registry with LDAP.

Troubleshooting network logs and resolving access management and provisioning workflow errors.

Created a chat project with Oracle DB

education

galgotias univ /bachelor of technology

Jul 2011 - Jul 2015, Greater Noida

Learn the basics of programming and Electronics.

Graduated with 7.8 CGPA in Electronics and Communication Engineering.

other experiences

- Taking up various roles to improve overall presentation and leadership skills at Toastmasters international.
- INFS certified nutrition and exercise expert.
- Weekly meeting coordination for more than a year in TISA.
- Helped multiple stammers lead a happier life by organizing workshops and conferences.
- Featured in company portal and media for stammering awareness programs.
- WWF volunteers for park and beach cleanup events.